<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Low-Code on Learner Loft</title>
    <link>https://learnerloft.com/tags/low-code/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Low-Code on Learner Loft</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.124.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://learnerloft.com/tags/low-code/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Oracle APEX</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/oracleapplicationexpress/chap1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/oracleapplicationexpress/chap1/</guid>
      <description>Imagine you want to build a big, fancy Lego castle. Each piece you use costs you money, and every time you need to fix or change something, it takes more time and money.
Now, instead of building it all by yourself, you have a team of builders. But coordinating all of them to work together smoothly can be really tricky. Sometimes they don’t understand each other well, which can lead to mistakes or delays.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Oracle APEX Three-Tier Architecture: A Comprehensive Guide</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/oracleapplicationexpress/chap2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/oracleapplicationexpress/chap2/</guid>
      <description>In the realm of web development, Oracle Application Express (APEX) stands out as a powerful tool for creating database-centric web applications. Its architecture, built on a three-tier model, provides a robust framework for developing, deploying, and managing applications efficiently.
In this article, we’ll delve into the intricacies of Oracle APEX’s three-tier architecture, exploring each tier’s role and how they work together to deliver seamless web applications.
Presentation Tier: At the forefront of Oracle APEX’s architecture lies the presentation tier.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Navigating Oracle APEX: A Tour of Key Development Components</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/oracleapplicationexpress/chap3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/oracleapplicationexpress/chap3/</guid>
      <description>As you sign into your APEX workspace, you’re greeted with a number of development components, each serving a distinct purpose.
Let’s take a guided tour through App Builder, SQL Workshop, Team Development, and Gallery, unraveling their functionalities along the way.
App Builder: Crafting Stunning Applications App Builder serves as your gateway to creating and managing applications effortlessly. Here, you design, develop, and deploy applications that are both visually captivating and highly functional.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oracle APEX — Rendering and Processing Page</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/oracleapplicationexpress/chap4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/oracleapplicationexpress/chap4/</guid>
      <description>Running an application in Oracle Application Express (APEX) might seem like a straightforward task, but behind the scenes, there’s a complex engine at work.
To shed light on this process, let’s delve into the two crucial processes that power the execution of APEX applications.
Page Rendering Imagine you’ve built a sleek and functional application using APEX, complete with interactive forms, dynamic reports, and engaging charts. When a user accesses your application, the APEX engine kicks into action.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Session ID, Session State, and Sessions</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/oracleapplicationexpress/chap5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/oracleapplicationexpress/chap5/</guid>
      <description>In the dynamic world of web application development, managing user sessions efficiently is paramount for delivering a seamless and personalised user experience. Oracle Application Express (APEX), a popular low-code development platform, provides robust tools for managing sessions effectively.
In this article, we’ll delve into the concepts of Session ID, Session State, and Sessions in APEX.
Understanding Session ID: At the heart of session management lies the Session ID, a unique identifier assigned to each user’s session.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Progressive Web App in Oracle APEX</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/oracleapplicationexpress/chap6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/oracleapplicationexpress/chap6/</guid>
      <description>Progressive Web Applications leverage modern web APIs giving users an experience that looks and feels like a native application. Your APEX applications can easily be defined as a PWA or Progressive Web Application to take advantage of advanced caching and improved performance. These applications can also be installed on your smartphone of choice with device-specific installation instructions.
Install Progressive Web App: The “Install Progressive Web App” feature in Oracle APEX allows developers to leverage the capabilities of PWAs within their applications.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Three Types of Applications in Oracle APEX : — Sample Apps, Starter Apps, and Custom Apps</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/oracleapplicationexpress/chap7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/oracleapplicationexpress/chap7/</guid>
      <description>Oracle Application Express (APEX) is a powerful tool for rapidly developing web applications on top of the Oracle Database. It provides developers with a range of features and functionalities to build robust applications efficiently.
One of the key aspects of APEX development is understanding the different types of applications it offers: Sample Apps, Starter Apps, and Custom Apps.
Let’s delve into each of these types to understand their purposes and benefits.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Interactive Report, Interactive Grid, and Classic Report -Oracle APEX</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/oracleapplicationexpress/chap8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/oracleapplicationexpress/chap8/</guid>
      <description>Oracle APEX offers various report types to display data effectively, catering to different user needs and preferences. Here’s an overview of the three main report types:- Interactive Report, Interactive Grid, and Classic Report:
Interactive Report Interactive Reports are highly customisable and user-friendly. They offer features such as sorting, filtering, highlighting, and aggregation directly within the report itself, providing users with a dynamic and interactive experience.
Key Features: Interactive Features: Users can sort, filter, and customise the display of data interactively without needing to reload the page.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is Page Zero / Global Page in Oracle APEX?</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/oracleapplicationexpress/chap9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/oracleapplicationexpress/chap9/</guid>
      <description>Oracle Application Express (APEX) includes a powerful feature called the Global Page, often referred to as Page Zero. This feature functions as a master page within your application, ensuring that certain elements are consistently rendered across multiple pages without the need for repetitive coding.
Here’s an in-depth look at what the Global Page is and how it can be effectively used.
Understanding the Global Page The Global Page is a unique type of page in Oracle APEX.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
