<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Data on Learner Loft</title>
    <link>https://learnerloft.com/tags/data/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data on Learner Loft</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.124.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://learnerloft.com/tags/data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What is SQL, Data, and Database? — Explained with Fun Examples!</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap1/</guid>
      <description>1. Introduction to SQL Imagine your room filled with video games, books, and snacks. Finding that one game you want to play? Total chaos! Now, think of SQL as your super-organized friend who knows exactly where everything is. SQL stands for Structured Query Language — a special way to communicate with databases, which are like digital storage rooms.
2. What is Data? Data is any piece of information you can think of — like your favorite song’s title, a photo of your pet, or your gaming stats.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Basic SQL Queries — SELECT, WHERE,UPDATE and DELETE</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap3/</guid>
      <description>Think of SQL queries as requests you make to find specific snacks in your snack box. Just like asking your friend to find your favorite candy in the snack box, SQL queries help you find specific information from a database.
Example:
Let’s say you have a table that lists all your favorite snacks and their quantities in your snack box, like this:
Now, using SQL queries, you can ask questions to find out specific information from this table.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>User-Defined Function (UDF) in SQL</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap8/</guid>
      <description>Let’s say, you have a special calculator that can perform a specific calculation, like doubling a number or calculating the average of a set of numbers. You can use this calculator whenever you need to perform that calculation, without having to write out the steps each time. In SQL, a user-defined function is like that special calculator — it’s a custom function that you can create to perform a specific task or calculation.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
