<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Beginners on Learner Loft</title>
    <link>https://learnerloft.com/tags/beginners/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Beginners on Learner Loft</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.124.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://learnerloft.com/tags/beginners/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Wireless Debugging on Xcode 9</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/swift/chap1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/swift/chap1/</guid>
      <description>Apple announced wireless debugging feature on Xcode 9 at WWDC 17.
Apple say Cut the Cord Choose any of your iOS or tvOS devices on the local network to install, run, and debug your apps — without a USB cord plugged into your Mac. Simply click the ‘Connect via Network’ checkbox the first time you use a new iOS device, and that device will be available over the network from that point forward.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Oracle APEX</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/oracleapplicationexpress/chap1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/oracleapplicationexpress/chap1/</guid>
      <description>Imagine you want to build a big, fancy Lego castle. Each piece you use costs you money, and every time you need to fix or change something, it takes more time and money.
Now, instead of building it all by yourself, you have a team of builders. But coordinating all of them to work together smoothly can be really tricky. Sometimes they don’t understand each other well, which can lead to mistakes or delays.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding HTML: The Backbone of the Web</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/html/chap1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/html/chap1/</guid>
      <description>HTML: The Backbone of the Web HTML, or HyperText Markup Language, is the backbone of web development and the foundation upon which every website is built. When you visit a website, what you see is a combination of different elements styled with HTML, and each plays a unique role. HTML provides a way to structure the content on the web, allowing you to define headings, paragraphs, images, links, and more.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is SQL, Data, and Database? — Explained with Fun Examples!</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to SQL Imagine your room filled with video games, books, and snacks. Finding that one game you want to play? Total chaos! Now, think of SQL as your super-organized friend who knows exactly where everything is.
SQL stands for Structured Query Language — a special way to communicate with databases, which are like digital storage rooms.
What is Data? Data is any piece of information you can think of — like your favorite song’s title, a photo of your pet, or your gaming stats.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generate timebase UUID in swift</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/swift/chap2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/swift/chap2/</guid>
      <description>First of all what is UUID? In software development as soon as we encounter assigning/fetching piece of data uniquely first thing that pops up in mind is UUID(universally unique identifier). so this is how wikipedia defines it.
A universally unique identifier (UUID) is an identifier standard used in software construction. A UUID is simply a 128-bit value. The meaning of each bit is defined by any of several variants.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HTML Text Formatting: Enhancing Your Web Content</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/html/chap2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/html/chap2/</guid>
      <description>HTML (HyperText Markup Language) is the foundation of web development, providing a structured way to create and format content for websites. One of the crucial aspects of HTML is its ability to format text, allowing web developers to emphasize, style, and organize their written content. In this article, we will explore various HTML tags used for text formatting, providing practical examples to demonstrate their usage and effectiveness.
Why Text Formatting Matters Text formatting is essential for improving the readability and user experience of web content.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Oracle APEX Three-Tier Architecture: A Comprehensive Guide</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/oracleapplicationexpress/chap2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/oracleapplicationexpress/chap2/</guid>
      <description>In the realm of web development, Oracle Application Express (APEX) stands out as a powerful tool for creating database-centric web applications. Its architecture, built on a three-tier model, provides a robust framework for developing, deploying, and managing applications efficiently.
In this article, we’ll delve into the intricacies of Oracle APEX’s three-tier architecture, exploring each tier’s role and how they work together to deliver seamless web applications.
Presentation Tier: At the forefront of Oracle APEX’s architecture lies the presentation tier.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the Power of SQL Commands:— DDL, DML, DCL, and TCL</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap2/</guid>
      <description>Ever wondered how massive websites like YouTube or Instagram handle tons of data? SQL (Structured Query Language) is the magical tool that makes this possible. SQL helps organize, manage, and retrieve information in databases, making it easy for you to keep track of everything! Here, we’ll explore different types of SQL commands used to manage databases, known as DDL, DML, DCL, and TCL. Get ready for an adventure through the world of SQL with some fun examples along the way!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Access specifier in Swift</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/swift/chap3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/swift/chap3/</guid>
      <description>What is Access specifier? Access specifier is keyword which helps in Access control of code block. Access control restricts access to the parts of your code from code in other source files and modules.
Encapsulation is one pillar of Object Oriented Programming and access specifiers helps in encapsulating.
What is Encapsulation?** Encapsulation is defined as the wrapping up of data under a single unit. It is the mechanism that binds together code and the data it manipulates.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mastering HTML Tables: A Comprehensive Guide with Examples</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/html/chap3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/html/chap3/</guid>
      <description>HTML tables have been a fundamental part of web design since the early days of the internet. They provide a structured way to display data in rows and columns, making it easier for users to interpret and analyze information. In this article, we’ll delve into the world of HTML tables, exploring their syntax, attributes, and examples to help you master this essential web design tool.
Understanding HTML Tables: HTML tables consist of rows and columns, organized within the &amp;lt;table&amp;gt; element.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Navigating Oracle APEX: A Tour of Key Development Components</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/oracleapplicationexpress/chap3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/oracleapplicationexpress/chap3/</guid>
      <description>As you sign into your APEX workspace, you’re greeted with a number of development components, each serving a distinct purpose.
Let’s take a guided tour through App Builder, SQL Workshop, Team Development, and Gallery, unraveling their functionalities along the way.
App Builder: Crafting Stunning Applications App Builder serves as your gateway to creating and managing applications effortlessly. Here, you design, develop, and deploy applications that are both visually captivating and highly functional.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Basic SQL Queries — SELECT, WHERE,UPDATE and DELETE</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap3/</guid>
      <description>Imagine this: You have a gigantic snack box filled with all kinds of snacks — chips, cookies, chocolates, and more. But finding exactly what you want is tough, especially with so many options mixed up together! SQL (Structured Query Language) is like a personal assistant for organizing and finding things in your snack box. Just like you would ask your friend to grab a specific snack for you, you can ask SQL to find, add, change, or remove data in a database.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Final in swift for Begineers</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/swift/chap4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/swift/chap4/</guid>
      <description>According to Apple document You can prevent a method, property, or subscript from being overridden by marking it as final. Do this by writing the final modifier before the method, property, or subscript’s introducer keyword (such as final var, final func, final class func, and final subscript).
Any attempt to override a final method, property, or subscript in a subclass is reported as a compile-time error. Methods, properties, or subscripts that you add to a class in an extension can also be marked as final within the extension’s definition.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HTML Forms: Building Interactive Web Experiences</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/html/chap4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/html/chap4/</guid>
      <description>HTML forms serve as the gateway for user interaction on the web, enabling users to submit data, provide feedback, and engage with web applications seamlessly. From login pages to contact forms, HTML forms are integral to capturing user input and driving interactive web experiences. In this article, we’ll dive deep into the world of HTML forms, exploring their structure, elements, attributes, and examples to help you harness their full potential in your web development projects.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oracle APEX — Rendering and Processing Page</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/oracleapplicationexpress/chap4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/oracleapplicationexpress/chap4/</guid>
      <description>Running an application in Oracle Application Express (APEX) might seem like a straightforward task, but behind the scenes, there’s a complex engine at work.
To shed light on this process, let’s delve into the two crucial processes that power the execution of APEX applications.
Page Rendering Imagine you’ve built a sleek and functional application using APEX, complete with interactive forms, dynamic reports, and engaging charts. When a user accesses your application, the APEX engine kicks into action.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mastering SQL Transactions: How COMMIT, ROLLBACK, and SAVEPOINT Work (With Fun Examples!)</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap4/</guid>
      <description>Imagine you’re a student, and you need to update your information in a school database. Let’s say you’re updating your age, but what if something goes wrong? Or, you decide to make a change but then realize you made a mistake? Don’t worry, SQL has your back! This is where COMMIT, ROLLBACK, and SAVEPOINT come into play.
These SQL commands help you manage changes to your database and make sure things run smoothly.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Xcode Tips - Create code snippet</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/swift/chap5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/swift/chap5/</guid>
      <description>What is code snippet? A small piece of a code in the program is known as a code snippet.
Wikipedia The snippet is a programming term for a small region of re-usable source code, machine code, or text. Ordinarily, these are formally defined operative units to incorporate into larger programming modules. Snippet management is a feature of some text editors, program source code editors, IDEs, and related software.
What is the use of code snippet?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Session ID, Session State, and Sessions</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/oracleapplicationexpress/chap5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/oracleapplicationexpress/chap5/</guid>
      <description>In the dynamic world of web application development, managing user sessions efficiently is paramount for delivering a seamless and personalised user experience. Oracle Application Express (APEX), a popular low-code development platform, provides robust tools for managing sessions effectively.
In this article, we’ll delve into the concepts of Session ID, Session State, and Sessions in APEX.
Understanding Session ID: At the heart of session management lies the Session ID, a unique identifier assigned to each user’s session.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HTML: Creating Links for Seamless Navigation</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/html/chap5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/html/chap5/</guid>
      <description>HTML, the cornerstone of web development, empowers developers to create hyperlinks, or simply links, that connect web pages together, enabling seamless navigation across the vast landscape of the internet. In this article, we’ll uncover the art of creating links in HTML, exploring various techniques and examples to enhance user experience and connectivity.
Understanding Links in HTML: Links are essential components of web pages, allowing users to navigate between different pages or resources with a simple click.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to update the view height with animation programmatically</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/swift/chap6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/swift/chap6/</guid>
      <description>Common problems of writing NSLayoutConstraint
Hello swift programmers, in this article we will look at how to use NSLayoutConstraint to elegantly handle the resize of view using some animation. let’s take an example
In apple notes app if you notice as soon as the keyboard comes up the text fields height changes with sweet animation. which look good to eyes and gives thoughts to the brain how to they do it?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Progressive Web App in Oracle APEX</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/oracleapplicationexpress/chap6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/oracleapplicationexpress/chap6/</guid>
      <description>Progressive Web Applications leverage modern web APIs giving users an experience that looks and feels like a native application. Your APEX applications can easily be defined as a PWA or Progressive Web Application to take advantage of advanced caching and improved performance. These applications can also be installed on your smartphone of choice with device-specific installation instructions.
Install Progressive Web App: The “Install Progressive Web App” feature in Oracle APEX allows developers to leverage the capabilities of PWAs within their applications.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adding Images and Other Page Elements with HTML</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/html/chap6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/html/chap6/</guid>
      <description>In the realm of web design, visuals play a pivotal role in capturing users’ attention and enhancing the overall aesthetic appeal of a website. HTML, the backbone of web development, offers an array of tags and elements to seamlessly integrate images and other page elements into web pages. In this article, we’ll explore how HTML enables developers to elevate their web design by adding images and other essential page elements with practical examples.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SQL Window Functions: Get Smarter with Data Analysis</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap6/</guid>
      <description>If you’ve ever wanted to perform complex calculations on your data without losing details or collapsing your results into a single row, you’re in the right place. Enter Window Functions in SQL! These powerful tools allow you to perform calculations across a set of rows, called a “window,” but without changing the number of rows you see in your results. It’s like using a magnifying glass to zoom into specific parts of your data without losing the overall picture.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to install iOS 14 beta</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/swift/chap7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/swift/chap7/</guid>
      <description>WWDC 2020 happened on Mon, 22 June 2020, as expected lot of new features announced and are available under the developer beta program. If you want to use them before the actual release follow these simple steps.
Note: As these update are beta there is possiblity of issue like data loss and bugs. so before starting the installation back up your data.
Step 1 Download iOS beta profile from https://developer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Three Types of Applications in Oracle APEX : — Sample Apps, Starter Apps, and Custom Apps</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/oracleapplicationexpress/chap7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/oracleapplicationexpress/chap7/</guid>
      <description>Oracle Application Express (APEX) is a powerful tool for rapidly developing web applications on top of the Oracle Database. It provides developers with a range of features and functionalities to build robust applications efficiently.
One of the key aspects of APEX development is understanding the different types of applications it offers: Sample Apps, Starter Apps, and Custom Apps.
Let’s delve into each of these types to understand their purposes and benefits.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HTML Frames: Enhancing Web Layouts with Frame Elements</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/html/chap7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/html/chap7/</guid>
      <description>HTML frames provide a powerful way to divide a web page into multiple sections, each with its own content. Despite their declining usage due to modern CSS techniques, frames remain a valuable tool for certain scenarios, such as creating sidebars or displaying content from different sources simultaneously. In this article, we’ll explore HTML frames, their syntax, attributes, and examples to help you understand and utilize them effectively in your web designs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aggregate Functions in SQL — Party Time with Candy Counting!</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap7/</guid>
      <description>Hey there, SQL enthusiast! Imagine you’re at a lively party with a bunch of friends, and there’s a big bowl of colorful candies on the table. Now, let’s say you want to figure out some cool stats about those candies: like the total number of candies, the average amount each friend has, or even which friend has a candy stash that puts everyone else to shame.
Believe it or not, SQL has some powerful tools, called aggregate functions, that do just this kind of “candy counting” on data!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Color theory</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/swift/chap8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/swift/chap8/</guid>
      <description>How to choose the right color?
What is Color theory? Practical guidance to create or choose the right colors for your needs. Yes, there are set of rule to create or choose colors and we will discover these rules in this article.
What is color? To answer what is color, we will have to understand the components of it
Hue: Name of the color is called hue. Saturation: Intensity of the hue is called saturation Value: Degree of lightness or darkness of the color Shade: Hue produced by adding black Tint: Hue produced by adding white Tone: Hue produced by adding grey Types of colors Color wheel is very useful in understanding the colors.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Interactive Report, Interactive Grid, and Classic Report -Oracle APEX</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/oracleapplicationexpress/chap8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/oracleapplicationexpress/chap8/</guid>
      <description>Oracle APEX offers various report types to display data effectively, catering to different user needs and preferences. Here’s an overview of the three main report types:- Interactive Report, Interactive Grid, and Classic Report:
Interactive Report Interactive Reports are highly customisable and user-friendly. They offer features such as sorting, filtering, highlighting, and aggregation directly within the report itself, providing users with a dynamic and interactive experience.
Key Features: Interactive Features: Users can sort, filter, and customise the display of data interactively without needing to reload the page.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>User-Defined Function (UDF) in SQL</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap8/</guid>
      <description>Imagine you run a smoothie shop, and each customer can customize their smoothie with different add-ons, like protein powder, extra fruit, and chia seeds. You want a quick way to calculate the total sale price of each smoothie based on its base price and the cost of each add-on. Instead of calculating the total price manually every time, we’ll create a user-defined function to do it for us!
Example: Defining the Function Let’s say you have a SmoothieSales table, and you want to calculate each smoothie’s total price by adding the base price and each add-on.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is Page Zero / Global Page in Oracle APEX?</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/oracleapplicationexpress/chap9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/oracleapplicationexpress/chap9/</guid>
      <description>Oracle Application Express (APEX) includes a powerful feature called the Global Page, often referred to as Page Zero. This feature functions as a master page within your application, ensuring that certain elements are consistently rendered across multiple pages without the need for repetitive coding.
Here’s an in-depth look at what the Global Page is and how it can be effectively used.
Understanding the Global Page The Global Page is a unique type of page in Oracle APEX.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Control Transfer Statements in swift- `continue, break, fallthrough in swift</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/swift/chap9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/swift/chap9/</guid>
      <description>In this article, we will look at the continue, break, fallthrough keywords in swift
Continue: A continue statement ends program execution of the current iteration of a loop statement and move to next iteration.
Ex: Increment the values of odd number in the array
func increment(array: [Int]) -&amp;gt; [Int] { var output: [Int] = []
for number in array { ///Check if value is even if number % 2 == 0 { ///number append to output array and move to next iteration output.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is Stored Procedure in SQL</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap9/</guid>
      <description>Imagine you’re baking a cake, and you have a recipe written down on a piece of paper. This recipe contains all the steps you need to follow to bake the cake, from mixing the ingredients to putting it in the oven. A stored procedure in SQL is like that recipe — it’s a set of instructions stored in the database that you can execute whenever you need to perform a specific task or set of tasks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adding a Custom Button with Delete Functionality — Oracle APEX Interactive Grid</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/oracleapplicationexpress/chap10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/oracleapplicationexpress/chap10/</guid>
      <description>To begin, let’s familiarize ourselves with the layout of the Interactive Grid toolbar. The toolbar is divided into seven distinct sections, each serving a specific function. Understanding this layout is crucial as we’ll use it to strategically assign our custom buttons. Here’s an overview of these sections:
Step by step guide : Navigate to your Oracle APEX application and locate the page containing the Interactive Grid where you want to add the custom button.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Class vs structure in Swift</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/swift/chap10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/swift/chap10/</guid>
      <description>In this article, we will learn about classes and Structs, the Difference between classes and structs and common features.
Class Classes are reference types. It means that if you assign an instance of the class to a variable, it will hold only the reference to the instance and not the copy.
class Person { var name: String init(name: String) { self.name = name } }
var ceo = SomeClass(name: &amp;ldquo;steve&amp;rdquo;) var newCeo = ceo //ceo and newCeo now reference the same instance!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Difference between Function and stored procedure in SQL</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap10/</guid>
      <description>Stored Procedures: Execution:
Stored procedures may or may not return a value. They can execute a series of SQL statements or perform actions such as data manipulation or transaction management. Usage:
Stored procedures are used to encapsulate a set of SQL statements for reuse and maintainability. They can be called from client applications or other stored procedures. Modifications:
Stored procedures can include data manipulation operations, transaction control, conditional logic, and error handling.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Data Load Definitions in Oracle APEX: A Beginner’s Guide</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/oracleapplicationexpress/chap11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/oracleapplicationexpress/chap11/</guid>
      <description>What is a Data Load Definition? Imagine you have a super cool app that needs to bring in lots of data from different files like Excel or CSV. A data load definition in Oracle APEX is like a set of instructions that tells your app how to do this properly. It’s like giving your app a map to follow when it gets new data.
How Do You Add Data Loading to Your App?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Data Load Definitions in Oracle APEX: A Beginner’s Guide</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/oracleapplicationexpress/chap12/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/oracleapplicationexpress/chap12/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Demystifying Bitcode: Understanding What, Why, and How for iOS Engineers</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/swift/chap11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/swift/chap11/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In the world of making iOS apps, there are lots of new things to learn. One of these things is Bitcode. If you’ve ever sent your app to the App Store, you might have heard about it. But what exactly is Bitcode, and why should iOS engineers care about it? In this blog post, we will break down what Bitcode is, its benefits, and how it fits into the way we make apps</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHOOSE and IIF — SQL</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap11/</guid>
      <description>Imagine you’re organizing a gaming tournament, and you want to assign a different prize based on the rank players achieved.
Let’s say you have the following rankings:
Ranking Table
Using CHOOSE CHOOSE function returns the value from a list of values based on the specified index.
SELECT CHOOSE(Rank, &amp;#39;Gold Medal&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;Silver Medal&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;Bronze Medal&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;Participation Prize&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;Participation Prize&amp;#39;) AS Prize FROM Rankings; Result:
Explanation:
The CHOOSE function takes the Rank as an index.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Swift Dispatch 101: Understanding Static, Dynamic, and V Tables!</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/swift/chap12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/swift/chap12/</guid>
      <description>Static Dispatch: Static dispatch refers to the process of determining which function or method to call at compile-time, based on the declared type of the variable or object. In simpler terms, it’s like deciding what action to take when you know exactly what type of thing you’re dealing with.
For example, if you have a Swift function that adds two numbers:
func add(\_ a: Int, \_ b: Int) -&amp;gt; Int { return a + b } And you call it like this:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Special operators in SQL</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap12/</guid>
      <description>There are several special operators that serve specific purposes beyond basic comparison and arithmetic operations.
Some of these special operators include: LIKE Operator: The LIKE operator is used to search for a specified pattern in a column. It&amp;rsquo;s commonly used with wildcard characters such as % (matches any sequence of characters) and _ (matches any single character).
SELECT \* FROM Employees WHERE FirstName LIKE &amp;#39;J%&amp;#39;; IN Operator: The IN operator is used to specify multiple values in a WHERE clause.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>For Beginners to Understand Constraints in Database</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap13/</guid>
      <description>Think of constraints in a database as rules that ensure data behaves properly, just like rules in a game. For instance, if you’re playing basketball, you can’t use your hands to touch the ball unless you’re dribbling or shooting. Similarly, constraints in a database ensure that data follows certain rules, like not allowing duplicate values in a column or making sure each student has a unique student ID.
Let’s say we have a table called “Students” with columns for StudentID, Name, and Age.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beginners Guide — Inner,Outer,left and right JOINS in SQL</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap14/</guid>
      <description>What are Joins? Imagine you have two lists of friends — one list with their names and another list with their hobbies. Now, you want to find out which friend has which hobby. This is where joins come in handy!
In databases, tables are like lists, and joins help us combine information from different tables based on a common piece of information, like a friend’s name or an ID.
Let’s consider two tables: friends and hobbies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>For Beginners to Understand Triggers in SQL</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap15/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap15/</guid>
      <description>Lets assume !! you have a magic toy box that automatically does something whenever you put a specific type of toy inside it. Triggers in SQL are like these magical rules that automatically perform actions in the database when certain events happen.
Example:
Let’s say you have a database table called “Orders” that stores information about orders placed by customers:
Trigger Example:
Now, imagine you want to keep track of any large orders (orders with a total amount over $100) automatically.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SQL — Temporary Tables</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap16/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap16/</guid>
      <description>Temporary tables are like a temporary workspace or desk that you set up when you need some extra space to work on a project. You can use this space to organize and manipulate data without affecting your main workspace (or database) permanently. Once you’re done with your task, you can clean up and remove the temporary workspace, and everything goes back to how it was before.
Example: Suppose you’re working on a school project where you need to analyze data about students’ grades and attendance.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Views in SQL</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap17/</guid>
      <description>Imagine you have a favourite playlist on your music app. Instead of going through all your songs every time you want to listen to your favorite tracks, you create a playlist that contains only the songs you love.
A view in a database is like that playlist — it’s a saved query that contains only the data you’re interested in, making it easier and faster to access.
Suppose we have a database with a table called “Students” that contains information about students, including their names and ages.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is a Cursor in SQL ?</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap18/</guid>
      <description>Think of a cursor in SQL like a pointer that allows you to navigate through a set of rows returned by a query, one row at a time. It’s like a virtual hand that can grab one row of data from a table, process it, and then move on to the next row.
Types of Cursors: There are mainly two types of cursors in SQL:
Implicit Cursors: These cursors are created by default when you execute a SQL query.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding REF_CURSOR in SQL</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap19/</guid>
      <description>Ever heard of something called REF_CURSOR Don’t worry if it sounds like gibberish right now. I’m here to break it down for you in the simplest way possible, so grab a snack and let’s dive in!
Imagine you’re at a library, and you ask the librarian to recommend some good books. Instead of giving you a list of book titles right away, the librarian hands you a special kind of card called a REF_CURSOR.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Difference between REF CURSOR and CURSOR</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap20/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap20/</guid>
      <description>To know the difference between ref cursor and cursor , first you should know what is cursor and ref_cursor.
REF_CURSOR: Dynamic Result Sets: REF_CURSOR, or reference cursor, is a data type that represents a cursor variable. It allows for dynamic result sets to be returned from stored procedures or functions in Oracle.
Data Pointing: REF_CURSOR does not hold actual data but acts as a reference to the result set generated by a query.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PRAGMA in PL/SQL</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap21/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap21/</guid>
      <description>Imagine you’re writing a story in your notebook, and sometimes you want to add special notes to yourself or your friend about how to read the story. You might write something like “Don’t worry about the spelling mistakes” or “Read this part very carefully.”
In programming, a pragma is a bit like those special notes. It’s a way for the computer to understand special instructions or hints about how to handle your code.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>For Beginners EXCEPTION in SQL</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap22/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap22/</guid>
      <description>Imagine you’re playing a game where you need to catch a ball. Sometimes, you might not catch the ball perfectly, and it might fall to the ground. But instead of giving up, you learn from your mistake and try again. In SQL, exceptions are like errors that occur during a task, but instead of crashing the program, they give you a chance to handle the error and continue with your task.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The differences in SQL</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap23/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/sql/chap23/</guid>
      <description>Truncate and Delete: Truncate: Truncate is like clearing the entire table at once. It removes all the rows from a table but keeps the table structure intact. It’s faster than DELETE but doesn’t allow for conditions.
TRUNCATE TABLE Students; Delete: Delete removes specific rows from a table based on conditions. It’s slower than TRUNCATE but allows for specifying conditions.
DELETE FROM Students WHERE Age &amp;gt; 18; Merge and Insert: Merge: Merge performs an INSERT, UPDATE, or DELETE operation based on the condition provided.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
