<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>HTMLs on Learner Loft</title>
    <link>https://learnerloft.com/html/</link>
    <description>Recent content in HTMLs on Learner Loft</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.124.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://learnerloft.com/html/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Understanding HTML: Structural Tags — Beginners</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/html/chap1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/html/chap1/</guid>
      <description>HTML, or HyperText Markup Language, is the backbone of web development. It is the standard markup language for creating web pages and applications. In this article, we’ll delve into the fundamentals of HTML, including its introduction and basic tags, to help you kickstart your journey into web development.
Introduction to HTML: HTML is a markup language used to structure content on the web. It provides a set of elements or tags that define the structure of a web page.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HTML : Formatting Text — Beginners</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/html/chap2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/html/chap2/</guid>
      <description>HTML, the cornerstone of web development, not only structures content but also allows for the formatting of text. In this article, we’ll explore various HTML tags used for text formatting along with practical examples to demonstrate their usage.
1. Bold Text: The &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt; tag is used to represent text with strong importance, typically rendered as bold by browsers.
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This is &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;bold&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt; text.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt; 2. Italic Text: The &amp;lt;em&amp;gt; tag is used to emphasize text, typically rendered as italic by browsers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mastering HTML Tables: A Comprehensive Guide with Examples</title>
      <link>https://learnerloft.com/html/chap3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerloft.com/html/chap3/</guid>
      <description>HTML tables have been a fundamental part of web design since the early days of the internet. They provide a structured way to display data in rows and columns, making it easier for users to interpret and analyze information. In this article, we’ll delve into the world of HTML tables, exploring their syntax, attributes, and examples to help you master this essential web design tool.
Understanding HTML Tables: HTML tables consist of rows and columns, organized within the &amp;lt;table&amp;gt; element.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
