<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Swift on Learner Loft</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/swift/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Swift on Learner Loft</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.124.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/swift/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Wireless Debugging on Xcode 9</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/swift/chap1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/swift/chap1/</guid>
      <description>Apple announced wireless debugging feature on Xcode 9 at WWDC 17.
Apple say Cut the Cord Choose any of your iOS or tvOS devices on the local network to install, run, and debug your apps — without a USB cord plugged into your Mac. Simply click the ‘Connect via Network’ checkbox the first time you use a new iOS device, and that device will be available over the network from that point forward.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generate timebase UUID in swift</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/swift/chap2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/swift/chap2/</guid>
      <description>First of all what is UUID? In software development as soon as we encounter assigning/fetching piece of data uniquely first thing that pops up in mind is UUID(universally unique identifier). so this is how wikipedia defines it.
A universally unique identifier (UUID) is an identifier standard used in software construction. A UUID is simply a 128-bit value. The meaning of each bit is defined by any of several variants.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Access specifier in Swift</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/swift/chap3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/swift/chap3/</guid>
      <description>What is Access specifier? Access specifier is keyword which helps in Access control of code block. Access control restricts access to the parts of your code from code in other source files and modules.
Encapsulation is one pillar of Object Oriented Programming and access specifiers helps in encapsulating.
What is Encapsulation?** Encapsulation is defined as the wrapping up of data under a single unit. It is the mechanism that binds together code and the data it manipulates.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Final in swift for Begineers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/swift/chap4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/swift/chap4/</guid>
      <description>According to Apple document You can prevent a method, property, or subscript from being overridden by marking it as final. Do this by writing the final modifier before the method, property, or subscript’s introducer keyword (such as final var, final func, final class func, and final subscript).
Any attempt to override a final method, property, or subscript in a subclass is reported as a compile-time error. Methods, properties, or subscripts that you add to a class in an extension can also be marked as final within the extension’s definition.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Xcode Tips - Create code snippet</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/swift/chap5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/swift/chap5/</guid>
      <description>What is code snippet? A small piece of a code in the program is known as a code snippet.
Wikipedia The snippet is a programming term for a small region of re-usable source code, machine code, or text. Ordinarily, these are formally defined operative units to incorporate into larger programming modules. Snippet management is a feature of some text editors, program source code editors, IDEs, and related software.
What is the use of code snippet?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to update the view height with animation programmatically</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/swift/chap6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/swift/chap6/</guid>
      <description>Common problems of writing NSLayoutConstraint
Hello swift programmers, in this article we will look at how to use NSLayoutConstraint to elegantly handle the resize of view using some animation. let’s take an example
In apple notes app if you notice as soon as the keyboard comes up the text fields height changes with sweet animation. which look good to eyes and gives thoughts to the brain how to they do it?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to install iOS 14 beta</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/swift/chap7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/swift/chap7/</guid>
      <description>WWDC 2020 happened on Mon, 22 June 2020, as expected lot of new features announced and are available under the developer beta program. If you want to use them before the actual release follow these simple steps.
Note: As these update are beta there is possiblity of issue like data loss and bugs. so before starting the installation back up your data.
Step 1 Download iOS beta profile from https://developer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Color theory</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/swift/chap8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/swift/chap8/</guid>
      <description>How to choose the right color?
What is Color theory? Practical guidance to create or choose the right colors for your needs. Yes, there are set of rule to create or choose colors and we will discover these rules in this article.
What is color? To answer what is color, we will have to understand the components of it
Hue: Name of the color is called hue. Saturation: Intensity of the hue is called saturation Value: Degree of lightness or darkness of the color Shade: Hue produced by adding black Tint: Hue produced by adding white Tone: Hue produced by adding grey Types of colors Color wheel is very useful in understanding the colors.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Control Transfer Statements in swift- `continue, break, fallthrough in swift</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/swift/chap9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/swift/chap9/</guid>
      <description>In this article, we will look at the continue, break, fallthrough keywords in swift
Continue: A continue statement ends program execution of the current iteration of a loop statement and move to next iteration.
Ex: Increment the values of odd number in the array
func increment(array: [Int]) -&amp;gt; [Int] { var output: [Int] = []
for number in array { ///Check if value is even if number % 2 == 0 { ///number append to output array and move to next iteration output.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Class vs structure in Swift</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/swift/chap10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/swift/chap10/</guid>
      <description>In this article, we will learn about classes and Structs, the Difference between classes and structs and common features.
Class Classes are reference types. It means that if you assign an instance of the class to a variable, it will hold only the reference to the instance and not the copy.
class Person { var name: String init(name: String) { self.name = name } }
var ceo = SomeClass(name: &amp;ldquo;steve&amp;rdquo;) var newCeo = ceo //ceo and newCeo now reference the same instance!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Demystifying Bitcode: Understanding What, Why, and How for iOS Engineers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/swift/chap11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/swift/chap11/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In the world of making iOS apps, there are lots of new things to learn. One of these things is Bitcode. If you’ve ever sent your app to the App Store, you might have heard about it. But what exactly is Bitcode, and why should iOS engineers care about it? In this blog post, we will break down what Bitcode is, its benefits, and how it fits into the way we make apps</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Swift Dispatch 101: Understanding Static, Dynamic, and V Tables!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/swift/chap12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/swift/chap12/</guid>
      <description>Static Dispatch: Static dispatch refers to the process of determining which function or method to call at compile-time, based on the declared type of the variable or object. In simpler terms, it’s like deciding what action to take when you know exactly what type of thing you’re dealing with.
For example, if you have a Swift function that adds two numbers:
func add(\_ a: Int, \_ b: Int) -&amp;gt; Int { return a + b } And you call it like this:</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
